A Finding Aid to the Sidney Simon Papers, circa 1917-2002, bulk 1940-1997, in the Archives of American Art AAA.simosidn
Archives of American Art
Sidney Simon papers
bulk 1940-1997
circa 1917-2002
AAA.simosidn
Archives of American Art
9.6 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor, painter, and educator Sidney Simon measure 8.0 linear feet and date from circa 1917-2002, with the bulk of the papers dating from 1940-1997. The collection documents Simon's career through biographical material, correspondence, writings and notes, subject files, sketches, sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Simon, Sidney, 1917-1997
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Sidney Simon papers were donated in 2009 by Rene Simon, widow of Sidney Simon.
Separated Materials note
Originals of loaned material, including biographical material, correspondence, sketchbooks, scrapbooks, and photographs of Sidney Simon were returned to Simon after microfilming. Loaned material is available on reel D210, but is not described in the container listing of this finding aid.
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives has two oral history interviews with Sidney Simon conducted by Paul Cummings in October 17-November 8, 1973 and the Karl E. Fortress taped interviews with artists, [1963-1985].
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical/Historical note
Sidney Simon (1917-1997) was a sculptor, painter, and educator who worked primarily in New York City and Truro, Massachusetts. Simon was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. At the age of 14, he won a place as a special student at the Carnegie Institute of Technology. He received a Bachelor of Fine Arts degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1934 and from the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts in 1936. Simon also studied at the Barnes Foundation from 1937-1940. Simon received professional recognition early in his career; he was awarded the Prix de Rome Collaborative Prize in 1939 and the Edwin Austin Abbey Fellowship in mural painting in 1945.
In 1941, Simon enlisted in the U.S. Army and served in the Army Corps of Engineers. Assigned to MacArthur's headquarters as an official war artist for the Southwest Pacific Theater, Simon was chosen to paint the signing of the peace treaty between the U.S. and Japan aboard the U.S.S. Missouri. He was discharged from the army with a Bronze Star and five presidential citations. In 1945, along with Bill Cummings and Henry Varnum Poor, Simon co-founded the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, where he later served as a director and a member of the Board of Governors. By the mid-1950s, Simon's interest shifted from painting to sculpture, creating works in wood, clay, and other media. Over the years, Simon collaborated with architects on a number of public and private commissions, including the doorway for the Downstate Medical Center, the Jewish Chapel at West Point, a playground sculpture for Prospect Park, and the totemic column for the Temple Beth Abraham. In addition to serving on the faculty at Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Simon also taught at the Art Students League, Brooklyn Museum, and Parsons School of Design. An active champion of artists' rights, Simon established the New York Artists Equity Association. He participated in solo and group shows at the Graham Gallery, Provincetown Art Association and Museum, and the Sculptors Guild, among other venues.
In 1997, Sidney Simon died at the age of 80 in Truro, Massachusetts. Simon was divorced from Joan Crowell in 1964. He is survived by his wife, Renee Adriance Simon and five children from his first and second marriages.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1940-1998 (Boxes 1, 9; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1936-2002 (Boxes 1-2; 1.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1943, circa 1960-1997 (Box 2; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1940-1941, 1951-1997 (Boxes 2-4, 9; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Sketches, 1937-1942 (Box 4; 1 folder)
Series 6: Sketchbooks, 1939-1995 (Boxes 4-5, 9; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, circa 1933, 1942-1998 (Box 5; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1978-1995 (Box 5; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 9: Photographs, circa 1917-1997 (Boxes 5-11; 3.0 linear feet)
Scope and Contents note
The papers of sculptor, painter, and educator Sidney Simon measure 8.0 linear feet and date from circa 1917-2002, with the bulk of the papers dating from 1940-1997. The collection documents Simon's career through biographical material, correspondence, writings and notes, subject files, sketches, sketchbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical material chronicles Simon's academic training and professional activities through curriculum vitae, biographical accounts, and awards. Included are letters and memoranda, many from Forbes Watson pertaining to Simon's service as a combat artist in World War II. Also found is a transcript of an interview with Simon recounting his experiences in the Southwest Pacific. Simon's personal correspondence with colleagues, friends, and family includes scattered letters from Jacqueline Helion, Penelope Jencks, William King, Burgess Meredith, among others. Many letters are illustrated by Sidney Simon and others. General correspondence includes letters from artists, galleries, museums, public and religious institutions primarily relating to Simon's exhibitions and commissioned projects. Among the correspondents are Castle Hill, Truro Center for the Arts, Colby College, André Emmerich, Eric Makler Gallery, Xavier Gonzalez, Graham Gallery, and the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. Interspersed among the files are letters of a personal nature. Other correspondence relates to Simon's faculty positions and his activities in professional organizations, e.g., Century Association, National Academy of the Fine Arts, and the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture.
Writings and notes include Simon's 1943 diary entries recording his activities in the Army Corps of Engineers, draft versions of writings and lectures, and notes. Included are Simon's lectures at the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture recorded on five sound discs. Subject files provide documentation on Simon's commissioned projects, select exhibitions and competitions, as well as his faculty positions and memberships in several arts organizations. Printed material consists of clippings, invitations, announcements, newsletters, and programs. Exhibition catalogs are of Simon's solo and group shows at galleries, museums, and art organizations from 1959-1966. Photographs are of Simon by Budd Brothers, Richard Pousette-Dart, and Bernard Gotfryd. There are a number of photographs of the artist in his studio and outdoors as well as of Simon's family and friends, including group photographs with Ellsworth Kelly, André Emmerich, Robert Motherwell, and Louise Nevelson. Also found are three personal and family albums and twenty-one photograph albums of Simon's paintings and sculptures.
Budd (Firm: New York, N.Y.).; Century Association (New York, N.Y.).; Colby College.; Emmerich, André; Gonzalez, Xavier, 1898-1993; Gotfryd, Bernard; Graham Gallery.; Hélion, Jacqueline; Jencks, Penelope; Kelly, Ellsworth, 1923- -- Photographs; King, William, 1925-; Meredith, Burgess, 1907-1997; Motherwell, Robert -- Photographs; Nevelson, Louise, 1899-1988 -- Photographs; Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts; Pousette-Dart, Richard, 1916-1992; Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture. School. -- Faculty; United States. Army. Corps of Engineers.; Watson, Forbes, 1880-1960; Art--Study and teaching; Artists' studios--New York (State)--New York--Photographs; Diaries; Educators--New York (State)--New York; Illustrated letters; Interviews; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Sound recordings; Transcripts; War artists; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Area; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives
- Biographical Material, 1940-1998; Series 1; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 1, 9
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes obituary notices, eulogies read at Sidney Simon's memorial service, and an American Immigrant Wall certificate of registration in memory of Simon's parents. A biographical account by Lincoln Kirstein details Sidney Simon's participation in the U.S. Army's mural competition for soldiers. Included are award certificates for the William Emlen Cresson Prize Memorial Fund and the National Sculpture Society's C. Percival Dietsch Prize. The series also includes a circa 1994 interview with Sidney Simon recorded on five sound cassettes and the memorial service held for Sidney Simon recorded on one sound cassette.
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1956-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Accounts, circa 1976-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - United States Army Corps of Engineers, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Award Certificates, 1988-1990; 1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Oversized material housed in Box 9
  - Transcript, Interview with Sidney Simon, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Interview with Sidney Simon, circa 1994; 5 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Remarks on Sidney Simon's 75th Birthday, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Eulogies for Sidney Simon, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memorial Service for Sidney Simon, 1997; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Certificate of Registration, The American Immigrant Wall of Honor, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Award Certificate from Box 1, Folder 9, 1988 (Box 9)
- Correspondence, 1936-2002; Series 2; 1.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Correspondence consists of letters, telegrams, faxes, postcards, and greeting cards. Included are letters of a personal nature between Simon and his artist friends and colleagues; correspondents discuss family matters, daily activities, and work projects. There are copies of Simon's outgoing letters and drafts of writings. Included are single letters from Fritz Bultman (1 postcard), Jacqueline Helion, Penelope Jencks, William King, Burgess Meredith, and Judith Shahn.
  General correspondence, for the most part is with galleries, museums, public and religious institutions relating to scheduling of exhibitions, commissioned projects, and sales of artwork. Other letters document Simon's active involvement in a number of professional organizations, such as the Architectural League of New York, Century Association, the National Academy of Design, the New York Chapter of Artists Equity Association, and the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture. Found are records of Simon's teaching positions at Amherst College, the Hopkins Center, Dartmouth College, and the New School. Among the correspondents are Castle Hill, Truro Center for the Arts, Colby College, André Emmerich, Eric Makler Gallery, Xavier Gonzalez, Graham Gallery, Ruth Millerick, Museum of Modern Art, Anne Poor, and the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. There are single letters from Sigmund Abeles, Benny Andrews, Varujan Boghosian, Helen Frankenthaler (1 postcard), Bernard Gotfryd, Walker Hancock, Milton Hebald, William King, Burgess Meredith, Paul Resika, Hughie Lee-Smith, among others. Found are illustrated letters by Simon and others, including a handmade Christmas card from William Zorach.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence, for the most part, is arranged in alphabetical order and filed chronologically thereafter. Correspondence is arranged as two subseries.
  2.1. Personal Correspondence, 1936-1943, 1966-1997
  2.2. General Correspondence, 1941, 1950-2002
  - Personal Correspondence, 1966-1997; 1936-1943; 2.1
    - A-B, 1966-1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - C-D, 1979-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - E-G, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - H-J, 1982-1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - K-L, 1979-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - M-P, 1979-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - R, 1980-1997; 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - S-T, circa 1980-1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - U-W, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified Names, circa 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - War Art Unit, Southwest Pacific Theatre, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Greeting Cards, 1950-1996; undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, 1941; 1950-2002; 2.2
    - A, 1963-1997 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - B, 1962-1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - C, 1960-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
    - D, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - E, 1962-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - F, 1978-1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - G, undated; 1962-1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - H, 1962-1996 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - I-K, 1959-1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - L, 1962-1996 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - M, 1960-1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - M, circa 1980-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - N, 1960-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - O, 1977-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - P-Q, 1960-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - R, 1960-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - S, undated; 1941; 1960-2002 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
    - T, 1966-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - U-V, 1960-1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - W-Z, 1962-1997; 1950; undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ilegible Names, 1966-1990; 1953; undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Unidentified, circa 1970-1996; undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Writings and Notes, circa 1960-1997; 1943; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Box 2
  This series includes drafts of Simon's writings on art-related topics, biographical accounts on Philip Guston and others, and a memorial tribute to Simon's long time friend, E.J. Kahn. Found are scattered lists of costs and sales of artwork. A notebook includes Simon's notes on his early career, the difference between painting and sculpture, and the challenges of working on architectural projects; presumably the notes were prepared for a lecture. Three lectures by Sidney Simon held at the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture are recorded on five sound discs.
  The series is arranged by format.
  - Diary, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1982-circa 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notebooks, circa 1980; undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lectures and Notes, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Various Writings and Notes, circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Lectures at Skowhegan, 1975-1983; 5 Sound discs (CD) (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
- Subject Files, 1940-1941; 1951-1997; Series 4; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 2-4, 9
  The majority of the files relate to Simon's public and private commissioned works. Also found is documentation on select competitions and exhibitions as well as teaching positions and professional memberships. Files contain biographical material, correspondence, letters of recommendation, exhibition schedules, minutes of meetings, organizational reports in addition to business-related documentation, e.g., contracts, loan receipts, agreements, sales and price lists. Among the printed materials are press releases, newsletters, clippings, brochures, and programs. Photographic materials are of Sidney Simon in his studio, his works in progress, and on-site installations.
  This series has been arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Academy of Arts and Letters, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1969-1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Architectural Sets, Negatives, circa 1963-1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Architectural Sculpture, Multiple Photograph Sets, 1956-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ars Nova Gallery, 1988-1989; undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Art Commission, Inc, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Art Students League, undated; 1973-1975; 1996 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Art Students League, Biographical Information, 1978-1997 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Artists Equity Association, 1987-1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Awards, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Berkeley Competition, circa 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Boston College Museum of Art, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Castle Hill, Truro, Massachusetts, 1988-1996 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Century Association, 1985-1996 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Circus Mobile, 1994-1996; 1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Commissions, 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Competitions, circa 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Competition, Art in Public Buildings, Dade County, Florida, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Contemporary Sculpture at Chesterwood" (1994 June 26-October 23) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Downstate Medical Center, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Family of Man Award, 1963-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Galleries, 1987-1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, Application Form, circa 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Long Point Gallery, 1981-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Maquettes, Synagogues, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mneme, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Models for Temple Beth Abraham and Walt Whitman High School, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Museums, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - National Sculpture Society, 1988-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Our Lady of the Angels Seminary, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - The New England Holocaust Museum, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Philadelphia Fountain Competition, Photographs and Negatives, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Police Memorial Battery Park Competition, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Prospect Park Playground, Animals, 1989; 1966 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Provincetown Art Association and Museum (Box 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Working Notes, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Photographs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Sidney Simon Retrospective Exhibition, 1995; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) Includes duplicate copy. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Sidney Simon Retrospective Exhibition, Edited Version, 1995; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Sidney Simon Retrospective Exhibition, 1995; 1 Videocassettes (Video 8) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Sales and Price Lists, 1951-1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Scattered Notes and Receipts for Commissions and Exhibitions, circa 1970-1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Sculptors Guild, Inc, 1989-1995; 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Synagogue Correspondence, Jewish Religious Art, 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Temple Beth Abraham, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Temple Maquette, The Wall of the Dead, circa 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Temple Maquette, Column of Light, circa 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Universities, 1976; undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wellfleet Exhibition, Photographs, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - West Point, 1985-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Woodland House, Papers and Accounts, 1963; 1985-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Works in Progress, Sculptures, circa 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Worldwide Plaza (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Contracts, Modern Art Foundry, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Sketches, Plans, and Source Material, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Articles, 1989-1995; 1945 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Photographs, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Oversized Sketches, Plans, and Source Material from Box 4, Folder 14, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
- Sketches, 1937-1942; Series 5; 1 Folders Box 4
  This series consists of sketches of figure studies and busts. Included is a preliminary study of Simon's Three Graces, which won the Posner Prize for Painting and two studies done for the Prix de Rome Collaborative Prize at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. Among the sketches are photographs of Simon's murals, drawings, and paintings depicting scenes of army life.
  - Early Sketches and Student Work, 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Sketchbooks, 1939-1995; Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-5, 9
  Nine sketchbooks contain drawings and preliminary sketches of nudes, figure studies, and portraits. Several sketchbooks were titled by the artist; some are annotated. Interspersed among the pages are loose sketches, notes, and clippings. A sketchbook contains photographic copies of Simon's drawings of the U.S. Army Corp's landing at Leyte in the Philippines; other drawings depict Simon's observations of the soldiers' activities aboard ship and in the field, preparing foxholes and dispensing medical care to the Filipinos.
  Sketchbooks are arranged in chronological order.
  - Sketchbook 1, 1939-1946 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sketchbook 2, "Landing at Leyte, Philippines" (Disbound), 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sketchbooks 3 and 4, "France, '48", 1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Sketchbook 5, "France, '49", 1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Sketchbook 6, "Notes 1952" (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Sketchbook 7, "Game Series", 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Sketchbook 8, 1955; undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Sketchbook 9, circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook 10, "Century Sketches", 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Sketchbook 9 from Box 5, Folder 1, circa 1960 (Box 9)
- Printed Material, 1942-1998; circa 1933; Series 7; 0.3 Linear feet Box 5
  Printed material includes invitations, announcements, newsletters, and programs. News and magazine clippings include exhibition notices, articles about Simon, and reviews of the artist's architectural projects. A clipping of the U.S. Army's landing on Wadke Island in the Philippines features a photograph of the invasion taken by Sidney Simon. Catalogs document Simon's participation in annual exhibitions held at the National Academy of Design, the National Sculpture Society, and the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. Miscellaneous printed material primarily consists of newsletters.
  This series is arranged by record type.
  - Clippings, 1942-1994; circa 1933 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1978-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Announcements, 1967-1998 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1959-1996 (Box 5, Folder 7-10)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Programs, 1967-1994; undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1985-1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Scrapbooks, 1978-1995; Series 8; 0.1 Linear feet Box 5
  A scrapbook for a proposed commission for the Jackson Memorial Hospital includes a handwritten proposal, design sketches, and cost breakdowns. Two scrapbooks of Simon's 1995 retrospective exhibition at the Provincetown Art Association and Museum contain a catalog and on-site installation views.
  Scrapbooks are arranged in chronological order.
  - Scrapbook 1, Jackson Memorial Hospital, Ambulatory Care Center, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook 2, Provincetown Art Association and Museum, "Sidney Simon, 40 Years of Work" (1995 August 18-October 30, Disbound) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbooks 3-5, Provincetown Art Association and Museum, "Sidney Simon, 40 Years of Work" (1995 August 18-October 30) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Photographs, circa 1917-1997; Series 9; 3 Linear feet Boxes 5-10
  Photographs are of Sidney Simon alone and with family members, friends, and colleagues. Many of the photographs are publicity shots of the artist in his studios in New York and Truro, Massachusetts or working on his sculptures outdoors. There are photographs of Sidney Simon at an exhibition held at the American Academy in Rome and of Simon with his family. Included is a group photograph of Sidney Simon with Robert Cronbach, Ellsworth Kelly, and Henry Geldzahler as well as individual photographs of Simon with André Emmerich, Robert Motherwell, and Louise Nevelson.
  Three personal and family photograph albums include photos of Simon as a child and youth with his mother, father, and other family members. An album of snapshots documents Simon's activities as artist-in-residence at the American Academy in Rome and at the Salzburg Seminar for American Studies; some printed material can be found interspersed among the pages. Twenty-one photograph albums house black and white copy prints and color snapshots that document Simon's paintings and sculptures.